<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://diegovilela.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://diegovilela.github.io//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-23T21:01:36-03:00</updated><id>https://diegovilela.github.io//feed.xml</id><title type="html">Diego Vilela</title><subtitle>Python Developer | Full-stack web development learner @Trybe</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My Mistakes in Becoming a Developer</title><link href="https://diegovilela.github.io//self-knowledge/my-mistakes-in-becoming-a-developer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Mistakes in Becoming a Developer" /><published>2021-05-23T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2021-05-23T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>https://diegovilela.github.io//self-knowledge/my-mistakes-in-becoming-a-developer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://diegovilela.github.io//self-knowledge/my-mistakes-in-becoming-a-developer">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#believing-only-very-smart-people-could-be-a-developer&quot;&gt;Believing only very smart people could be a developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#not-networking&quot;&gt;Not networking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#taking-too-long-to-change-of-career&quot;&gt;Taking too long to change of career&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#not-applying-the-learned-skills-frequently-enough&quot;&gt;Not applying the learned skills frequently enough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#have-focused-on-programming-languages-rather-than-on-solving-problems&quot;&gt;Have focused on programming languages rather than on solving problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;believing-only-very-smart-people-could-be-a-developer&quot;&gt;Believing only very smart people could be a developer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t remember how neither why, it was a long time ago, but I assumed only incredibly intelligent people could be developers. Sometimes I still suffer from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome&quot;&gt;impostor syndrome&lt;/a&gt;, but the fact is that anyone with a healthy brain can learn absolutely anything with discipline and hard work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-networking&quot;&gt;Not networking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I studied by myself for too long. I should have attended more conferences. They are a great way to meet experienced professionals, possible employers, and get updated. It’s also a good idea to talk to peers about your insecurities. Very often, great developers have had the same concerns. They can share their experiences or even mentor you somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;taking-too-long-to-change-of-career&quot;&gt;Taking too long to change of career&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to realize I wanted to actually work as a software developer. Maybe due to the wrong belief I had, but also because I already had a quite stable job. The lesson learned was that now I think carefully about my values and what kind of person I want to be before investing time and energy into something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-applying-the-learned-skills-frequently-enough&quot;&gt;Not applying the learned skills frequently enough&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, I identified a problem in my office that demanded a lot of the personnel’s time. So I implemented a system to mitigate the waste of time and it was that. I rarely added new features or refactored the code. In my defense, I had many other duties for sure, but I could have kept a constant improvement process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-focused-on-programming-languages-rather-than-on-solving-problems&quot;&gt;Have focused on programming languages rather than on solving problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like programming. So I focused on it instead of the problems I needed to solve. It’s ok to learn about all details of tools you use once you don’t forget that businesses make money out of solving problems and the software we deploy must create value for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="self-knowledge" /><summary type="html">Table of Contents Believing only very smart people could be a developer Not networking Taking too long to change of career Not applying the learned skills frequently enough Have focused on programming languages rather than on solving problems</summary></entry></feed>